Metropolitan Medical Society Records
Metropolitan Medical Society Records
1892-1968
Metropolitan Medical Society
1 linear foot (1 carton)
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Statement
The Metropolitan Medical Society was founded in 1861 with the goal of advancing medical science and facilitating social relationships among members through presentations, discussions, and an exchange of ideas. Meetings were hosted 9 months out of the year at the residences of members.
Scope and Content
The majority of the collection is comprised of minutes from the monthly meetings (1892-1963), and also includes several programs, letters, treasurer's reports, and other assorted documents.
Arrangement of Collection
The meeting minutes are in chronological order within several folders and notebooks. Loose documents have been divided by document type with the original chronological order preserved.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Medicine -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies, etc.; Metropolitan Medical Society
Container List
- Metropolitan Medical Society Records
  - Correspondence, 1892-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1898-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1905-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1932, 1940, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 75th Anniversary and historical sketch, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 77th Anniversary, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous programs and amendments to constitution (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1894-1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting attendance and active members, 1899-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1911-1918 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1931-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minute books, 1895-1897, 1898-1900, 1901-1911, 1918-1924, 1925-1931 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minute book, 1896-1905 (Box 1)
  - Booklet of Constitution, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Meeting attendance notebook, 1899-1916 (Box 1)
  - Small notebook with members list, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Address book (Box 1)
  - Notebook (Box 1)
Provenance
Donated by the Metropolitan Medical Society.